const e="englishlit",t=200,o=77,a=[{id:48,question:"What figure of speech does the following quotation contain? A life's but a walking shadow (Macbeth)",option:{a:"a metaphor ",b:"an image ",c:"a synecdoche ",d:"an allusion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:49,question:"Which of the following statement is most true about poetry? ",option:{a:"the meanings of words are more important than their sounds ",b:"the sounds of words are more important than their meanings ",c:"the sounds of words are often more important than their meanings ",d:"sounds and meanings of words are of little consequence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:50,question:"Which of these best define exposition in drama?",option:{a:"the author's own general introduction to the play ",b:"the author's early exposure of his dramatis personae to conflict ",c:"introduction to the characters and the general problem with which the play deals",d:"the first performance of the play on stage."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:51,question:"When the speaker in a poem cannot be identified with poet, that speaker is called: ",option:{a:"a persona ",b:"a dramatic persona ",c:"a soliloquist",d:"a ventriloquist."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:52,question:"Which of these definitions best described a lyric? ",option:{a:"a short poem",b:"a short poem in which the poet is speaking",c:"a poem expressing a personal idea, feeling or mood",d:"a poem divided into stanza."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:53,question:"An autobiographical novel is: ",option:{a:"a novel written about another novelist ",b:"a true account of a novelist's life by himself ",c:"a novel in which h the novel 1st draws mainly on materials from his own life ",d:"a novel using the' I' pronoun."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:54,question:"Plot in prose fiction is best defined as:  ",option:{a:"the cause and effect sequence of events  ",b:"the brief summary of events  ",c:"the central event  ",d:"the subject-matter of a novel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:55,question:"Which of these is not true about unity of action in a novel? ",option:{a:"action may be unified through a single main character  ",b:"action may be unified by being set in one place  ",c:"action may be unified by many characters  ",d:"action may be unified by using set in one consistent point of view."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:56,question:"Action in a novel is best defined as:  ",option:{a:"the summary of the novel’s story  ",b:"what the characters do or say in the novel  ",c:"the numerous sub-plots of the novel put together ",d:"the totality of all the episodes in a novel leading to the conclusion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:57,question:"Suspense in a novel means:  ",option:{a:"the postponement of the hero’s death till the last possible moment ",b:"the intense emotions that the author conveys  ",c:"the inconclusive end of a novel  ",d:"when we are curious about what happens next in a novel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:58,question:"A realistic novel is one in which the characters are:  ",option:{a:"real   ",b:"historical ",c:"just of above average intelligence  ",d:"the types that we meet in everyday life."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:59,question:"Theme is best defined as:  ",option:{a:"the subject – matter of a novel or play ",b:"the central idea in a play or novel  ",c:"the point of view in that novel  ",d:"the sum-total of all the characters’ experiences"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:60,question:"What kind of repetition is used in the extract?  ",option:{a:"anaphora ",b:"single word repetition  ",c:"line repetition  ",d:"phrase repetition."},section:`Read the following extract from a poem to answer questions 
Among rocks, I am the loose one,
Among arrows, I am the heart
Among daughters, I am the recluse,
Among sons, the one who dies young
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:61,question:"A part from emphasis, what other effect does the repetition have?  ",option:{a:"makes the poem rhythmical  ",b:"makes the poem tedious  ",c:"makes the poem -notonous  ",d:"makes the poem exhilarating."},section:`Read the following extract from a poem to answer questions 
Among rocks, I am the loose one,
Among arrows, I am the heart
Among daughters, I am the recluse,
Among sons, the one who dies young
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:62,question:"The following line from a poem:  Western wind, when will thou blow? Is an example of: ",option:{a:"rhetorical question  ",b:"caesura  ",c:"alliteration  ",d:"nature imagery."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:63,question:"Identify the odd one out of these types of imagery  ",option:{a:"visual imagery  ",b:"tactile imagery  ",c:"synesthesia  ",d:"literal imagery."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:64,question:"When a poet uses mainly soft vowel sounds in a poem, the texture of the poem is ",option:{a:"mellifluous ",b:"harsh ",c:"assonantal ",d:"neutral "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:65,question:"The sounds in the following lines may be described as an example of: The moan of doves in immemorial elms, and murmuring of innumerable bees ",option:{a:"alliteration ",b:"euphony ",c:"cacophony ",d:"a mixture of all the above."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:66,question:'"The man dies in him who keeps silent in the face of tyranny." This statement can be described as: ',option:{a:"Metaphoric ",b:"Literal ",c:"Tragic ",d:"A smile."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:67,question:"The literary technique in which a reader is taken to the past of a current action in known as:",option:{a:"rewinding ",b:"fast forward ",c:"flashback ",d:"repetition."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:68,question:"One rhyme scheme typical of the English sonnet is ",option:{a:"abba abba cde dce ",b:"abba abba cde cde ",c:"abab cdcd efef gg ",d:"abcd babb cde cc."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:69,question:"The speaker of the above except is a ",option:{a:"son of Lord Montague ",b:" nephew to Lady Capulet ",c:"kinsman to the Prince ",d:" servant to Paris."},section:'" ... This is a Montague, our foe; A villain, that is hither come in spit. To scorn at out solemnity this night. William Shakespeare: Romeo and Juliet I:V,61-63. ',image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:70,question:`In Gbemisola Adeoti's "Naked Soles", the expression "red milk of grief' means `,option:{a:"wine ",b:"sea ",c:"ink ",d:"blood."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:71,question:"Farce thrives on ",option:{a:"big events ",b:"promotion ",c:"absurdity ",d:"incidents."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:72,question:"A short witty statement is an ",option:{a:"epistle ",b:"eulogy ",c:"epigram ",d:"anecdote."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:73,question:"In a narration, the first person is ",option:{a:"the author ",b:"a participant ",c:"the publisher ",d:"an observer."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:74,question:"Literary device that creates a mental picture of   a situation is ",option:{a:"imagery ",b:"symbolism ",c:"flashback ",d:"epilogue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:262,question:"In the play, Fasuwa represents the",option:{a:"new culture",b:"patriarchy",c:"old order",d:"African civilization."},section:"Based on J.C. De Graft’s Sons and  	Daughters.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:263,question:"The play opens with a conversation between Aaron and Awere about",option:{a:"Aaron’s choice of course",b:"Maanan’s encounter with the lawyer",c:"George and Kofi",d:"Hannah and George."},section:"Based on J.C. De Graft’s Sons and  	Daughters.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:264,question:"‘I still think you can do something about it... persuade him; make him see how frustrating the whole business is bound to be for you.’  <em>The whole business in the excerpt above refers to </em>",option:{a:"marriage proposal",b:"career choice",c:"business contract",d:"political transition."},section:"Based on J.C. De Graft’s Sons and  	Daughters.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:265,question:"The central conflict in the play is",option:{a:"religious",b:"romantic",c:"generational",d:"communal."},section:"Based on J.C. De Graft’s Sons and  	Daughters.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:266,question:"The change in fortune is achieved in the play when",option:{a:"James agrees that Aaron and Maanan should study what they want",b:"Lawyer B harasses Maanan in his office",c:"Haanah, James’ wife convinces him",d:"Aaron and Maanan agree to read the courses James chooses for them."},section:"Based on J.C. De Graft’s Sons and  	Daughters.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:267,question:"‘l will be brief, for my short date of breath Is not so long as is a tedious tale.’ The statement above is in reference to the speaker’s",option:{a:"retirement",b:"imminent death",c:"state of health",d:"short-tempered nature."},section:"Based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:268,question:"Romeo’s death becomes inevitable because",option:{a:"Friar Lawrence’s letter is not delivered",b:"Juliet is married to Paris",c:"Romeo kills Tybalt in a duel",d:"Juliet has committed suicide."},section:"Based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:269,question:"The multiple deaths in the play serve as a punishment for",option:{a:"imposing life partner on Children",b:"treating others with hatred",c:"disobeying one’s own parents",d:"shedding kinsmen’s blood."},section:"Based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:270,question:"The major reason for Juliet’s grief is",option:{a:"the death of her cousin",b:"her reluctant marriage to the County",c:"the banishment of her lover",d:"her imminent death."},section:"Based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:271,question:"The chorus in the prologue of the play is essentially meant to",option:{a:"foreshadow the play",b:"highlight the characters",c:"estimate the actions",d:"introduce the play."},section:"Based on George Orwell’s Nineteen  	Eighty-Four.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:272,question:"In the novel, Big Brother metaphorizes a",option:{a:"totalitarian authority",b:"benevolent leader",c:"revolutionary leader.",d:"party brotherhood."},section:"Based on George Orwell’s Nineteen  	Eighty-Four.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:273,question:"In the novel, Orwell attempts to",option:{a:"satirize the artificiality of a machine ‘controlled society",b:"eulogize the beauty of the socialist system",c:"condemn the disgusting hypocrisy of all communist    	 systems",d:"laud the boundless possibilities of the human intellect."},section:"Based on George Orwell’s Nineteen  	Eighty-Four.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:274,question:"Winston Smith begins his rebellion against the power of the state by",option:{a:"purchasing arms",b:"keeping a private diary",c:"opposing the law",d:"educating the youth."},section:"Based on George Orwell’s Nineteen  	Eighty-Four.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:275,question:"The Ministry of Truth is concerned with",option:{a:"news, entertainment, education and fine arts",b:"propaganda, war, publishing and enlightenment",c:"investigation, propaganda and fine arts",d:"economic affairs, education and propaganda."},section:"Based on George Orwell’s Nineteen  	Eighty-Four.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:276,question:"The events following the ceremony confirm Meka’s",option:{a:"disillusion with the whites",b:"satisfaction with the medal",c:"contribution to the colonialists",d:"admiration for the church."},section:"Based on Ferdinand Oyono’s The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:277,question:"“ ‘ By my mother!’ said Engamba. The night rat doesn’t tell what happened to him in the dark! Men are born and die...”  In the statement above, The night rat doesn’t tell what happened to him in the dark! refers to",option:{a:"the Whiteman’s treatment of Meka",b:"Meka’s treatment of the medal in the whitewashed circle",c:"people’s unwillingness to talk about how Whiteman treat them",d:"people’s freedom of expression."},section:"Based on Ferdinand Oyono’s The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:278,question:"In the novel, the expression  <em>fobreak the leg of an antelope</em> means",option:{a:"hunting",b:"marriage",c:"fighting",d:"honeymoon."},section:"Based on Ferdinand Oyono’s The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:279,question:"Ona has to leave her father’s house because",option:{a:"of her love for Agbadi",b:"that is the tradition",c:"her father is dead",d:"of the safety of her child."},section:"Based on Buchi Emecheta’s The Joys of Motherhood.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:280,question:"Nnaife’s conscription into the army is portrayed as part of",option:{a:"family conflict",b:"British oppression",c:"family tradition",d:"societal intrigue."},section:"Based on Buchi Emecheta’s The Joys of Motherhood.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:281,question:"The attitude of Nnu Ego when she was told that her Chi would not give her a child is one of",option:{a:"indifference",b:"despair",c:"apathy",d:"hope."},section:"Based on Buchi Emecheta’s The Joys of Motherhood.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:282,question:"The subject matter of Adeoti’s Naked Soles is",option:{a:"soul and mind",b:"hunger and strife",c:"suffering and despair",d:"hatred and bitterness."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:283,question:"Rubadiri’s <em>An African Thunderstorm</em> appeals to the readers’ sense of",option:{a:"sight and taste",b:"feeling and sight",c:"smell, taste and hearing",d:"sight, smell and hearing."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:284,question:"‘The experts, of course Disagree. The urine test they ordered Said, Negative.’ The lines above from Acqah’s “In the Navel of the Soul” depict",option:{a:"contradiction",b:"inevitability",c:"progress",d:"awareness."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:285,question:"In Kunene’s ‘A Heritage of Liberation,’ freedom is to be achieved through the efforts of",option:{a:"the old generation",b:"new generation",c:"present generation",d:"successive generations."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:286,question:"Launko’s ‘End of the’ War suggests that war brings about",option:{a:"ultimate solution to all problems",b:"partial solution to problems",c:"multifaceted problems",d:"only temporary relief."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:287,question:"The persona in the poem <em>Give Me The Minstrel’s Seat</em> discourages",option:{a:"togetherness",b:"hatred",c:"isolation",d:"poverty."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:288,question:"Marvel’s To ‘His Coy Mistress’ is written mainly in",option:{a:"alternate rhymes",b:"blank verse",c:"heroic couplets",d:"middle rhymes."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:289,question:"The attitude of the poet-persona to bats, in Lawrence’s Baf is one of",option:{a:"satisfaction",b:"reverence",c:"hatred",d:"repulsion."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:290,question:"The language used, in Eliot’s ‘The Journey of the’ Magi is generally",option:{a:"difficult",b:"complex",c:"simple",d:"complicated."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:291,question:"In Cope’s <em>Sonnet VII</em>, poetry is",option:{a:"a popular act",b:"a boring act",c:"an idle hobby",d:"a useless undertaking."},section:"Based on selected poems from Johnson, 	R. et al (eds.): New Poetry from Africa; Soyirvka, W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African Poetry; Maduka, C.T. et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination Guides; Nwoga, D. I. (ed.): West African Verse and Adeoti G.: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:292,question:"An interlude is a brief",option:{a:"presentation in the interval of a dramatic performance",b:"play before the main dramatic performance",c:"presentation after the main dramatic performance",d:"dialogue between two persons."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:293,question:"An epic is a heroic story which includes",option:{a:"ballad",b:"lyric",c:"myth",d:"dialogue."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:294,question:"Farce can be described as a dramatic piece marked by",option:{a:"movement from serious to the light-hearted mood",b:"comic and exaggerated actions",c:"actions devoid of meaning",d:"gloomy actions with momentary reliefs."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:295,question:"A long story narrating a series of complicated events is called a",option:{a:"saga .",b:"discourse",c:"monologue",d:"harangue."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:296,question:"Oxymoron is the use of two contrasting words that are",option:{a:"placed far apart",b:"different in meaning",c:"placed side by side",d:"similar in meaning."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:297,question:"A line or a group of lines repeated in the course of a poem is called",option:{a:"chorus",b:"refrain",c:"repetition",d:"prologue."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:298,question:"Limerick is a light verse which consists of five lines that are",option:{a:"anapestic",b:"trochaic",c:"spondaic",d:"dactylic."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:299,question:"A short narrative or lyrical poem intended to be sung is a",option:{a:"leich",b:"lay",c:"lauda",d:"letrilla."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:300,question:"A figurative device in which a statement is made and then withdrawn is referred to as",option:{a:"metanoia",b:"metaphysical",c:"metalanguage",d:"metalepsis."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:301,question:"A literary work which imitates another in a distorted form is called",option:{a:"exodium",b:"isocohen",c:"metonymy",d:"burlesque."},section:"Based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:302,question:"‘You do not have to be brutal to be a soldier, or rather you are brutal not because you are a soldier, but because there is a sadist, a rapist, a fascist and a murderer in you who is waiting for war and army uniforms to give them expression.’ ( Festus lyayi: Heroes ) The speaker here contends that",option:{a:"soldiers are generally wicked",b:"human nature has to do with a profession",c:"soldiers are characteristically gentle",d:"the latent brutality in man finds expression in war."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:303,question:"‘But the towering earth was tired of sitting in one position. She moved, suddenly, and the houses crumbled, the mountains heaved horribly, and the work of million years was lost.’ The subject matter of the passage is",option:{a:"earthquake",b:"Demolition",c:"flood",d:"storm."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:304,question:"The image depicted is one of",option:{a:"destruction",b:"dejection",c:"happiness",d:"admiration."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:305,question:"The tone of the poem above is",option:{a:"satiric",b:"affectionate",c:"indifferent",d:"sympathetic."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:306,question:"Life, though a vanity Yet, not purposeful In drawling<br> resignation Life’s spice is in strive<br> From the extract above, the poet suggests that",option:{a:"life is full of care",b:"there can’t be life without strive",c:"life is worthwhile without care",d:"strive makes life worth living."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:307,question:"The subject of the poem above is",option:{a:"a prostitute",b:"the lying father",c:"the son",d:"the orphan."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:308,question:"The dominant rhetorical device in the excerpt above is",option:{a:"rhyme",b:"alliteration",c:"repetition",d:"onomatopoeia."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:309,question:"The expression “The child is the father of the man” in the poem above is an example of",option:{a:"paradox",b:"metaphor",c:"simile",d:"ellipsis"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:310,question:"The technique employed in narrating the excerpt above is",option:{a:"flashback",b:"stream of consciousness",c:"foreshadowing",d:"play-within-the-play."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:311,question:"The poet’s tone above can be described as",option:{a:"lamentative",b:"satiric",c:"imploring",d:"adoring."},section:"based on Literary Appreciation.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"}],i={subject:e,status:200,total:77,data:a};export{a as data,i as default,t as status,e as subject,o as total};
